Guide to the Goldsboro Banyar and Banyar Family Papers 1727-1904 (bulk, 1740-1840) MS 39
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Goldsboro Banyar
  - Subseries I.5: Patents, deeds and other land conveyances
    - Deed and Grant of Wharfage with survey map to William Lawrence, with supporting documents (New York City), 1806-1820 (Box OS large, Folder Banyar OS 155)
    - Letters patent for three lots in the village of Lewiston, Niagara County, 1808 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 156)
    - Survey maps: Plan of Great Jones, Map of Kingsborough, and unidentified area along Hudson River, undated (Box OS medium, Folder Bayar OS 157)
    - Blank deeds, circa 1800 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 158)
    - Loose seals (detached from 18th century deeds), circa 1770 (Box 9A, Folder unknown container)
    - Calendar of land documents (Box 9A, Folder unknown container)
  - Subseries I.6: Business and household accounts
    This subseries contains accounts and receipts reflecting Banyar's land transactions, quitrents, land surveys, bonds and mortgage obligations, stock transactions, wheat sales, tax receipts, and purchases of household goods and services. Also included are papers relating to the purchase of Banyar's Pearl Street residence in Albany.
    - Account books, 1769-1770, 1791-1797, 1805 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Indenture of servitude (draft) and labor accounts, 1785-1803, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Accounts and receipts (quitrents, mortgages, bonds, etc.), 1760-1806, 1815, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Accounts, receipts and indentures (land patents), 1770's-1790's (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Accounts, receipts and other documents relating to the Schorharie Patent, 1799, 1809. undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Account book and receipts relating to Wallace's Patent, 1773, 1789-1813 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - John Wigram's minutes respecting Goldsborough and Wallace's Patent, 1809 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - John Wigram's accounts respecting Wallace's Patent, 1812-1816 (Box OS medium, Folder Banyar OS 159)
    - Bills and receipts for land surveys, 1768-1774, 1792-1802 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Receipts (primarily for bonds and mortgage obligations), 1799-1815, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Stock certificates, 1792- 1814 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Accounts of wheat sales (primarily Bordman and Hillhouse), 1799-1809 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Accounts of wheat sales (primarily Bordman and Hillhouse), 1799-1809 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 160)
    - Receipts (household goods, clothing, groceries, wheat, etc.), 1760's-1800's, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Papers relating to purchase of Pearl Street residence in Albany, 1791 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Receipts for goods and services; household accounts, 1774-1815, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Receipts for goods and services, 1773-1791 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 161)
    - Tax receipts, 1800-1813 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Bank book, Goldsboro Banyar, 1800-1814 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Banknotes, Bank of Albany, 1800-1804 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 162)
  - Subseries I.7: Legal and estate papers
    This subseries includes bond and mortgage indentures, powers of attorney, decrees, orders, and various other legal documents relating to Banyar's personal and business affairs. Of particular interest is a bill of sale and manumissions papers for a slave. Also included are wills and estate papers of Banyar and other family members. In addition there are wills of other people connected to the family, including Lawrence Reade, who leaves an interesting bequest to Mary Barron, a "free mulatto woman in the Island of Jamaica," and her three children Sara Reade, Lawrence Reade and Ann Reade.
    - Chancery Court, papers filed in Rutsen v. Van Rensallear, 1788-1789 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Bond and mortgage indentures, 1766, 1794-1814 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Bond indenture and related papers, William Edgar and Chauncy Belknap, 1803-1823 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1773-1815 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Legal documents (decrees, orders, petition of insolvent debtor), 1762, 1773, 1788, 1799, 1818 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Estate of Abraham and Martha Mortier, 1767-1795, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Wills and estates of Joseph Reade, Lawrence Reade and Francis Stephens, 1769, 1773, 1783, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Estate of Alexander Colden, 1773, 1784, 1790, 1793 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Guardianship of Mary Ballard Beckford (granddaughter of George Clarke), 1784-1790 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Marriage certificate of Goldsboro Banyar and Elizabeth Appy, 1767 February 3 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Bill of sale and manumission papers for slave named Frank, 1795, 1801 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Wills of Goldsbrow Banyar, 1792-1810 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 163)
    - Receipts and accounts relating to Goldsbrow Banyar Estate, 1815-1840 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Sales of wheat for the estate of Goldsbrow Banyar, 1812-1820's (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Accounts of Goldsborough LeRoy Banyar, devisee, 1822 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Estate of Jacob and Martha Leroy, 1814-1815 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Estate of Jacob and Martha LeRoy, 1817-1822, 1831, 1837 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      See also
      Later accounts from the estate of Jacob and Martha LeRoy will be found in Box 21, Folder 5.
    - Wills of Banyar family members, 1765-1886 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Appointment of Frederick W. Smith to Lieutenant in the US Navy, 1813 July 24 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 164)
      Access Restrictions
      Contains presidential signature
- Series II: Campbell P. White and Harriet (Banyar) White
  This series consists primarily of the papers of Banyar's grandson-in-law, Campbell Patrick White, who married Banyar's granddaughter Harriet Banyar LeRoy in 1816.
  An Irish immigrant, Campbell Patrick White (1787-1859) became a successful New York merchant and Tammany politician. His father, Dr. John Campbell White, founded White and Sons Distillery in Baltimore, and Campbell and his older brother Robert White operated a New York branch of this business. Campbell White was also elected to Congress as a Jacksonian Democrat, serving from 1829 to 1835. Upon the death of Goldsborough LeRoy Banyar, Campbell White took over management of the Banyar family estate, including the family's real estate holdings.
  Also included in this series are some papers of Campbell White's brother, Robert White (d. 1847). Robert White was for many years the cashier of the Bank of Manhattan, until he resigned around 1840 amid allegations of misfeasance. A bachelor, Robert White was closely involved with his nephews, the children of Campbell and Harriet, and apparently lent them substantial amounts of money for their brokerage business. A letter to Robert from his father suggests that he may have had problems with alcoholism.
  Papers include correspondence as well as financial and legal documents spanning the period from 1818 to the 1850's. Correspondence concerns the business dealings of Campbell and Robert White, including various financial transactions, the family distillery business, management of the Banyar estate, and the dispute with the Bank of Manhattan. Correspondence of Campbell White also touches on political issues, including currency and anti-rent legislation and the assassination attempt on Andrew Jackson.
  Letters of frequent and/or significant correspondents with Campbell White have been foldered separately. These include business associates and agents William Slosson, Robert Ludlow, Marcus T. Reynolds, James Dexter, William Wason; diplomat David Baillie Warden; Baltimore lawyer and statesman Reverdy Johnson; Senator Levi Woodbury; and various others identified in the box and folder list. Of particular interest are some letters sent by William Wason during the 1949 cholera outbreak, when Campbell White's family relocated to the Rockaways.
  Correspondence of Robert White concerns business with the Bank of Manhattan and the ante-bellum cotton trade. There are also several folders of other documents concerning the Bank of Manhattan, including some concerning the allegations against Robert White.
  There is correspondence from and between other family members, including Goldsborough LeRoy Banyar, John Campbell White (Campbell's father), John White (Campbell's brother), Henry White (Campbell's brother) and his son John White (Campbell's nephew), Joseph White (Campbell's brother) and his son William Pinkney Whyte (Campbell's nephew), and Campbell and Harriet's children John C. White, Mary White and Ann White. Letters address business as well as family matters; some of the letters relate to a dispute between Campbell White and his brothers in Baltimore over business dealings, which led his nephew William Pinkney Whyte to legally change the spelling of his name.
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence and ephemera
    This subseries includes correspondence and related papers, as well as a few folders of ephemera and family keepsakes.
    - Letters from Campbell White, 1820-1843 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Campbell White, 1844-1854 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Campbell White (undated and fragments) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Campbell White, 1818, 1825-1835 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Campbell White regarding political patronage, 1832-1849 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Campbell White, 1836-1843 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Campbell White, 1844-1853, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Letters and certificates regarding Campbell White's appointments in New York State Militia, 1820-1845 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Drafts and other documents relating to currency legislation, 1826-1833, 1846, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding anti-rent legislation, 1850-1851 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence of William Slosson, 1823-1845, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence of David Baillie Warden (Paris), 1823-1844 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence of Robert Ludlow, 1828-1850, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence of Marcus T. Reynolds (Albany), 1832-1849, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence of James Dexter (Albany), 1832-1850 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence of James Dexter regarding Banyar estate, 1833-1837 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence of William Wason, 1833-1849 July 14 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence of William Wason, 1849 July 16 - 1850, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of Levi Woodbury, 1837 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence of James G. King (regarding Manhattan Company), 1840-1843 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence of E.S. Derry, 1840-1849 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence of Andrew Stevenson (Richmond), 1841-1843 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Belfast correspondents (Same Lake, E. Beggs, Edmond Getty), 1841-1851 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence of Emily Harper, 1843-1847, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence of James Smith, Southwark Bank (Philadelphia), 1843-1849 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence of Charles O'Connor, 1843-1850 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence of Reverdy Johnson, 1844-1845 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence of J. Glenn (Baltimore), 1849-1850 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Various correspondents, 1824-1852, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Envelopes, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence of Robert White, 1820-1846, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and accounts relating to cotton business, 1811, 1832-1837 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Papers relating to Bank of Manhattan, 1819-1839, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to Bank of Manhattan, 1840-1844 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Goldsborough LeRoy Banyar (brother-in-law of Campbell White), 1817-1859, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Letters from John C. White (father) to Robert and Campbell White, 1824?-1834 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Letters from John White (brother) to Campbell and Robert White, 1825-1848, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Letters from Henry White (brother) to Campbell White3, 1832-1845 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Letters from John C. White (nephew) to Campbell White and Mary White, 1845-1851, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Letters from Joseph White (brother) to Campbell White), 1844-1850 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Letter from William Pinkney Whyte (nephew) to Campbell White, 1849 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence of John C. White (son of Campbell White), 1833-1852, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence of Mary White (daughter of Campbell White), 1850, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence of Ann White (daughter of Campbell White), undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Other White family correspondence, 1814, 1821, 1848-1849, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Printed material (voting list for 24th Congress, invitation to 28th anniversary of Tammany Society, appeals for aid), 1846, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1828, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Calling cards and hair locks (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Commonplace book of Campbell White; school exercise of John C. White, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified manuscript, circa 1830 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Subseries II.2: Financial and legal papers
    This subseries consists of various business and household receipts, real estate documents, and legal and estate papers.
    - Accounts and receipts, Campbell White, 1807-1850, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Receipts and bank notes, Campbell White, 1805-1869, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Household and contractor receipts, Campbell White, 1825-1859, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Accounts and receipts, Robert White, 1826-1843, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Accounts and receipts, Robert White, 1836-1840, undated (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 165)
    - Receipts, assorted, 1825-1851, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Accounts and receipts, John White & Company, 1817-1847, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Account book, John White & Company, 1831-1833 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Accounts and receipts, John C. White, 1840's-1850's, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Bank books, receipt books and cancelled checks, 1829-1848, undated (Box 17)
    - Bank books, Bank of New York, 1842-1847 (Box OS small, Box-folder Banyar OS 165A)
    - Checkbooks, Robert White and Manhattan Co.; signature stamp, 1832-1845, undated (Box 18)
    - Check receipts, 1842-1845 (Box 18A)
    - Accounts and receipts, stocks and bonds, 1813-1854, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Accounts, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Accounts (including estates and rents), 1814-1851, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Tax assessments, 1819-1856 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Receipts, Martha LeRoy, Harriet White, and others, 1812-1858 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Inventory of furniture, Harriet Banyar White, 1821 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - White household receipts, 1822-1852 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - White household receipts and accounts, 1825-1850, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Mortgages, bonds and releases, 1817-1857 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Patents and mortgages, circa 1830's (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Deeds, grants and leases, 1816, 1835-1857 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 166)
    - Deeds, 1827-1850, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Record book of deeds, 1828-1864 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Leases, 1837-1854 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Releases, 1836-1855 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Rental and other land agreements; maps, 1820-1853, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Search for judgments, 1809, 1819-1839, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Legal claims and contracts relating to Manhattan water lots, 1818-1849, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Inventory of land holdings, circa 1837 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Legal claims and lawsuits, 1828-1837 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Legal claims and lawsuits, 1838-1861 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Legal claims and lawsuits (White family members), 1833-1854 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Legal papers (drafts), 1825-1843, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Blank legal forms, 1829, undated (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 167)
    - Estate account books (Dan LeRoy, Dr. Benjamin Payne, William Lawrence), 1801-1820, 1832, undated) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Estate account books, Cornelia Ludlow, 1837-1838 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Estate account books and inventories, Campbell White and Harriet Banyar White, 1859, 1886-1903 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Estate accounts, Jacob and Martha LeRoy, 1829-1859 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Earlier accounts of this estate will be found in Box 12, Folders 1-2.
    - Estate accounts, heirs of Goldsbrow Banyar, 1820-1840, undated (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 168)
    - Will and estate papers, Goldsborough LeRoy Banyar, 1841-1842 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Probate and will of Ann Dulany, 1828 (Box OS large, Folder Banyar OS 169)
    - Exemplification of probate and new will of Daniel Dulany, 9 January 1924 (Box OS large, Folder OS 35)
    - Estate papers, Ann White, 1827-1847 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Estate papers, Ann White, 1829-1841 (Box OS medium, Folder Banyar OS 170)
    - Estate papers, Ann White (insurance policies), 1815-1828 (Box OS small, Folder Banyar OS 171)
    - Estate papers, Charlotte White, 1840- 1841, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Estate of William Edgar, correspondence and legal papers, 1823-1844, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Estate of William Edgar, accounts, 1822-1842, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - State Marine Insurance Company (papers relating to lawsuit), 1835-1843, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - State Marine Insurance Company (financial statements), 1831-1840 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Marine insurance policies for shipments of gin and cotton (Ocean Insurance Company, Jackson Marine Insurance Company), 1832-1837 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Fire insurance policies and premiums (primarily Eagle Fire Company), 1823-1852 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Plan of Regulation West of Broadway (survey), 1849 (Box OS medium, Folder Banyar OS 172)
- Series III: Goldsborough Banyar (formerly John Campbell White)
  This series spans the period from 1872 to 1904 and consists primarily of papers relating to the routine management of the properties in the Banyar estate by Campbell and Harriet's son John White, who in accordance with his uncle's will changed his name to Goldsborough Banyar. There is also a small amount of personal correspondence of John White's sisters, Ann, Cornelia and Mary. Receipts include local businesses, many with pictorial billheads.
  - Correspondence with Department of Docks, 1874-1875 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Business correspondence, 1872-1876, 1885 January - April (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Business correspondence, 1885 July - December, 1888-1899 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Business correspondence, 1900 May - October (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Business correspondence, 1900 November - December (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Business correspondence, 1901 January - April (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Business correspondence, 1901 May - August (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Business correspondence, 1901 July - December (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Business correspondence, 1902 January - August (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Business correspondence, 1902 September - December (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Business correspondence, 1903 January - June (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Business correspondence, 1903 July - December (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Business correspondence, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Personal correspondence, Ann White, 1900-1910 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Personal correspondence and ephemera, Cornelia White and Mary White, 1899-1904, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Account books, 1860's - 1880's (Box 24A, Folder unknown container)
  - Accounts, 1887-1890 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Schedule of unsold lots in the Goldsborough and Rapalye's Patents, 1890 May (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Accounts, 1891-1893 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Accounts, 1894 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Accounts, 1895-1897 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Account books, 1896, 1898-1899 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Accounts, 1898 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Accounts, 1900-1901 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Accounts, 1902 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Accounts, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Accounts, 1904 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "Tax lists" (accounting book for White family properties), 1857-1899 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1872-1876 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1887-1890 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1891-1893 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1894-1896 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1897-1899 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1900-1901 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1902 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Taxes and assessments, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1878-1880 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1888-1893 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1895-1899 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1900-1902 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1903-1904 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Stock certificates; certificates of inspection, 1899-1904 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Estate papers, Goldsborough Banyar (formerly John White), 1904, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Leases and other agreements, 1872-1886 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Leases and other agreements, 1889-1904 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, 1891, 1893-1898 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1899-1900 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Receipts, 1901 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, 1902 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, 1903 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Receipts and handwritten notes, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Bank books, Goldsborough Banyar, 1892-1904 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Cancelled checks, 1902-1904 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Check book, with cancelled receipts and blank checks (National Bank of Commerce), 1900-1904 (Box 29, Folder 2)